All right, so we have successfully compiled our graph and it is ready to use. As I told you earlier that doing builder.compile, it is actually making it runnable. I can say that make it linechain runnable so that you can use the graph.invoke here.
Perfect. Now if you pass your parameter, basically your input to graph.invoke, it is going to be like this. Graph.invoke, the one thing you have to remember here that while you are invoking your graph, you have to make sure that whatever the keys you have used here, those keys you have to provide while invoking this.
So you have your input text. Output text we don't have currently. In fact, output text will be modified internally and it will be created internally.
So what we do here, we are going to pass a dictionary here and that is going to be our initial state.
So you can say that our initial state or user input. Initial state or you can say that the user input. Whatever you prefer you can say.
So I can say that here this is going to be my initial state.
So in the initial state we have our input underscore text. Inside the input text we have our hello. Something like this. And then this initial state you can directly pass inside this graph.invoke here. Alright. So in this what happened here. So basically you are passing this dictionary here with the input text. We are not passing here output text that will automatically... that will be created automatically.
Let's go ahead and run this and then see the our output. Now if you notice here our current state is having input text. That is the hello output is like this. Input text is this. And then final state is coming like this. Input text is like this. And output text automatically gets added. And this is the final output. Once your graph executed. The one thing you notice here. Have you noticed that? A difference here.
Before graph when we executed these nodes in the nested manner. Then we were getting only our output text. Input text was not there. Let me just show you here that. Alright.
We were seeing here output text only. This is what I was telling you at that time. Once you build your graph then it is LangGraph's responsibility to maintain the graph.
So this overall overall canvas is going to maintain simple state. Whatever keys are passed at the start of your graph. That keys are going to be maintained throughout this particular graph execution. Unless or until it is removed or additional keys are added. If no additional keys are added or if no keys are removed. Then you are going to get all the keys.
Which have been defined in your custom state. Alright.
If you want to pass additional state here. You can also pass the additional states as well. For example. You can see like this.
Some other state. Alright.
If you execute this. If you execute this. Then you will notice here that this particular state is not taken. So basically this particular state is removed from the execution. Why? Because you see this initial state goes to the start here. Alright.
And as soon as it goes into the start. What happen here. This whole thing gets converted using a simple state. Simple state have only input text. Your simple state does not have some other state. Or some other field. Then what happen here. It is going to remove these fields. It is going to use only these fields.
If you want to utilize the output text. If you want to utilize the output text as well. Then you can utilize that output text as well. For example. Let's say you can do it like this. The one thing here. I want to show you here. That although you pass something here.
With the output text. But if you execute your graph. Then what happen here. It is going to remove this. Because internally what happen. It is going to overwrite your output text. So basically output text is controlled by directly your prefix, suffix node and your process input node. Alright. It doesn't matter whatever value you pass here as a state to your output text. That is going to be modified.
internally. Now I hope that it is pretty much clear to you. Now I hope that it is pretty much clear to you. And in this particular section. I hope that you have understood that. What is the state and how state flows from one node to the another node. The one thing you notice here that all these messages are getting added. But that part I have not shown you here. Because that is not required as of now. Later on as we move forward. I will show you how you can create your state in such a manner.
that it can maintain these historical messages as well. As of now. As of now you will notice here that. As your graph is executing one node to the another node.
It is not maintaining any historical messages. It is just maintaining the current state. So there are ways to add.
Or you can say that there are methods which you can utilize to add these historical messages. In your line graph state. So those things we will be seeing in coming sections. In this particular course. And overall. I hope that it is helpful to you. Please do not forget to leave your rating and the feedback for this course. I also have a YouTube channel. I request you please come to my channel. KGP Talkie. And subscribe this channel. So that whenever I update.
or I put update or I put update on my channel. You will be able to get the latest and the real-time update. Alright. I will see you in next lesson.